Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have an
intermediate level lesson
all about cell phones.
That's right, we're going to be buying a
cell phone or also known as a mobile phone.
So before we jump into
the dialogue, let's take
a look at a specific type of
phone on vocabulary preview.
Very cabliery preview.
Well the name of this
phone is kind of funny,
it's called a smart
phone, it's very popular
these days, things like
the Apple iPhone or the
HTC Hero, these are
examples of a smartphone.
That's right, so basically
a smartphone has
additional functions, more
than just a normal mobile phone.
For example, you can check
your email on a smartphone.
Yeah, so the thing that
makes a smartphone
different from a normal mobile
phone is that it's like a small computer.
You can do things like
Marco said, send emails,
or take photos, edit photos, use applications,
things like that from your phone.
Okay, so we're going
to be talking about
smart phone, so let's listen to
the dialogue for the first time.
Hello sir, may I help you?
Yeah, I accidentally dropped
my phone in the toilet.
I see, well you've come to the right place.
We have over 100 models of more than
20 leading mobile phone manufacturers.
Sounds good, I don't want it to be too
expensive, maybe something mid-range.
We have this new HTC
smartphone, it comes with
the Android OS so you
can download applications.
It also has a built-in camera,
MP3 player, and touch screen.
It works on the 3G network so you have fast
access to the internet wherever you are.
What about Wi-Fi?
Of course, you can access the internet
from any hotspot, as well as from home.
One last thing, is it waterproof?
All right, we're back,
now have you ever done
this, have you ever dropped
your phone in the water?
Have you ever damaged the phone like that?
Luckily no, knock on
wood, but I have a good
friend who dropped
his in the toilet and
had to buy a new one,
yeah, so this is not made up.
It's actually more common than what people
think, but we'll get to that in a bit.
Why don't we take a look at five
key words in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
This first word is very
important because in
this particular dialogue, we're
talking about the HTC smartphone.
This is a special kind
of phone, and it has
an Android operating
system, or OS, so Android
is something that
Google came up with, and
they have this operating system
that they're giving away for free.
If you want to use it,
you can use it, you can
make a whole new phone
using this operating system.
So the operating
system, like Windows, or
what's the map one
called, Tiger OS, Tiger OS,
you have these optics,
Linux, yeah, Linux,
these are like the
interface that allows you
to use your computer and
to interact with it, and so
they're different for
different kinds of computers.
The same is true of a smartphone.
Exactly.
So that's what we're looking at today.
If you see this word,
Android, it's a proper
noun, and as Catherine
mentioned, it's the
name of the OS or operating
system developed by Google.
So we're taking a look at a
smartphone that uses the Android OS.
All right, now this
phone not only carried
this operating system,
but also an MP3 player.
That's right, so an MP3
player is a device that
plays songs for you, so
songs can be stored as MP3s.
And a good example of
an MP3 player is an iPod.
And iPod, exactly, or, and for many of you,
you're listening to this podcast as an MP3
file through an MP3 player.
So that's the name, we usually say MP3.
Exactly.
And another feature of
this special smartphone
is that you can use
it on the 3G network.
What is a 3G network market?
All right, so a 3G network
is a third generation
network, which allows
more information to be sent.
So not only can you
send voice like a normal
cell phone network,
but now you can send
pictures, or you can download
information like, for example, your email.
So this is a new 3G network, it allows
you to send more information, more data.
Exactly.
3G, third generation.
And in addition to this, our customer
wants to know about Wi-Fi, okay?
Wi-Fi, you hear this a
lot when you go to a
hotel or a restaurant, they
say we have Wi-Fi access.
Right.
And Wi-Fi stands for wireless fidelity, so
it's basically internet that has no wires.
You don't need to connect
your computer to anything.
You just log on and use the internet.
All right.
So look out for that when
you're in a cafe next time.
Do they have Wi-Fi?
Usually there's a sign on the wall.
And finally, this customer wants to
know, is this great phone waterproof?
What is waterproof?
All right.
So if you have a watch,
for example, and you
can take this watch into a swimming pool
or the ocean, it means it's waterproof.
So it resists water, it won't
get damaged if it gets wet.
Great.
So I could say that I have
a waterproof jacket, right?
So that means that when
I go in the rain, my clothes
don't get wet because they
don't go inside the fabric.
Mm-hmm.
Also, and there are
many things waterproof as
watches or waterproof
cameras, I've never really
seen a waterproof mobile phone though,
I think that's a good invention, maybe.
That would be.
All right.
So those are five key
words for language
takeaway, why don't we listen to
the dialogue again, and we'll be back.
Hello, sir.
May I help you?
Yeah.
I accidentally dropped
my phone in the toilet.
I see.
Well, you've come to the right place.
We have over 100 models of more than
20 leading mobile phone manufacturers.
Sounds good.
I don't want it to be too expensive.
Maybe something mid range.
We have this new HTC smartphone.
It comes with the Android OS
so you can download applications.
It also has a built-in camera,
MP3 player and touch screen.
It works on the 3G network so you have fast
access to the internet wherever you are.
What about Wi-Fi?
Of course.
You can access the internet from
any hotspot as well as from home.
One last thing.
Is it waterproof?
All right, we're back, so now we have
three phrases for you on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Okay, this first phrase
is a way of expressing
something, so we're
going to give you a formula.
First word is leading, so leading
mobile phone manufacturers.
So when we use the word leading,
we're saying that it's leading in industry.
That means the most important
manufacturers in a kind of industry.
Right, so it's one of the
biggest is one of the best.
And if we want to change
the noun, we can say
for example, the
leading car manufacturer.
Exactly.
So in Japan, I wonder who
the leading car manufacturer is?
Is it Toyota?
Toyota.
And we could also say that about clothing.
The leading clothing manufacturer in
America is, I have no idea cotton, maybe.
Cotton, right?
So you can use many
other nouns and well, if
you want to drop the
manufacturer, you can
say the leading brand in cosmetics or
the leading supplier of medical equipment.
So this means the person
or the company with
the most, that's the most
important in an industry.
Right.
And going back to one
of the features of the
mobile phone, we talked
about the built-in camera.
Now this structure
is interesting, built-in.
Well, we can say that things are built-in
when they are a part of something else.
For example, a built-in
camera is a part of a phone.
It's not a camera and a phone.
Two different devices.
They're put together.
We can also say this about cabinets.
No, you can buy cabinets and you can put
them in your house and keep things in them.
But we often have built-ins.
That means that they're stuck on the wall.
You can't take them away.
Right.
So those are called built-ins
because they're part of the wall.
So built-in camera is a part of the phone.
Right.
So you can pretty much use this structure
with two products that are combined as one.
For example, the
cabinets that Katherine
mentioned or if your
refrigerator has a television
incorporated, right, you can say this
refrigerator comes with a built-in television.
Or very common is the
laptop with built-in speakers.
So that means we don't
have to bring speakers
with us every time we
want to use the laptop.
There's small speakers inside the computer.
Right.
Very good.
And we have one last phrase.
One last phrase.
One last thing.
All right.
So that's our phrase.
One last thing.
Oh, before you go, one last thing.
So this is often said when
someone's leaving a conversation.
So I'm going to say, OK, Marco,
I've got to go run and do something.
I'll see you later.
Right.
Oh, wait, wait, one last thing.
Wait.
What?
OK.
So now I'll wait.
So one last thing is
a way to say, no, wait.
Hold on.
I have to tell you one last thing.
So yeah, as you say, you
can use it as a fixed phrase.
One last thing.
Or before I go, one last thing.
Can you take out the last
thing we have to talk about?
Right.
And this was our last word.
So why don't we listen to
our dialogue for the last time?
Hello, sir.
May I help you?
Yeah.
I accidentally dropped
my phone in the toilet.
I see.
Well, you've come to the right place.
We have over 100 models of more than
20 leading mobile phone manufacturers.
Sounds good.
I don't want it to be too expensive.
Maybe something mid-range.
We have this new HTC smartphone.
It comes with the Android OS
so you can download applications.
It also has a built-in camera,
MP3 player, and touch screen.
It works on the 3G network, so you have fast
access to the internet wherever you are.
What about Wi-Fi?
Of course.
You can access the internet from
any hotspot, as well as from home.
One last thing.
Is it waterproof?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
All right, we're back.
And I actually read
somewhere that many girls
have this accident because they place
their mobile phones in their back pockets.
So when they go to the
bathroom, they accidentally--
the phone accidentally drops
out and falls into the toilet.
I heard a different explanation
for this common problem.
Maybe not very appropriate.
Boys have this problem
because they take their phone
to the bathroom, and they play with
them when they're using the bathroom.
I've also heard this that
you're maybe checking your
messages or checking your
email when your bathroom, it falls.
Just falls.
Yeah, so I think boys and
girls all have this problem.
Be careful with your phones.
Those smartphones
are still pretty expensive.
Yes, they are.
All right, so if you have
any questions, any doubts,
you can contact us at EnglishPod.com,
and we'll see everyone there.
Bye, everyone.
Bye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(upbeat music)